Inventory of the Barnes Family Papers 1797-1926, 1818-1875
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1830-1849., 54 items. (Box-folder 1-2:43-96)
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Papa" N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes, Greenfield, near Jeffersonton, Culpeper C[ounty], [Virginia], 15 Dec. 1840.[?]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:68)
    Re: news of events in Falmouth; reminds NWBB to come and get her at Christmas.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] Tomlin] Barnes, Green Field, Jeffersonton, P. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 12 Feb. 1841., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:69)
    Re: MWB's anniversary and Armistead's 16th birthday; accounts of Armistead's visit home; family news including Lucy's health and Robert's forthcoming marriage.
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, Fredericksburg, [Virginia], to "Father" N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes, n.p. With a note by L., 1 Mar. 1841., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:70)
    Re: all are well except Grandma; General Harrison passed through Fredericksburg; hope MWB will profit by your good advice; Aunt Bal[sora] will teach the boys this spring and summer.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Green Field, Jeffersonton p. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 23 Apr. 1841., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:71)
    Re: family news; Robert's marriage; MWB fell down the potato hole and bruised herself; health of family members.
  - R[obert] W. Tomlin, Office of Blue Ridge Residency, Balcony Falls, [Virginia], to N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes, Fox's Mills P. 0., Acquire County, Virginia, 12 Sept. 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:72)
    Re: sister Margaret's health and RWT's work with a survey of the New River.
  - Margaret W. Barnes,, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper Co[unty], Virginia, 20 May 1842[?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:73)
    Re: MWB is worried about MWTB's going home safely; Papa's health and George and Bevy's health; sent MWTB's shoes by Dennis.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper Co [unty], Virginia, 18 June l842[?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Re: death of Mr. Brooke; sends messages to family members.
  - R[obert] W. Tomlin, Office of Blue Ridge Residency, Balcony Falls, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton p. o., Culpepper C[oun]ty, Virginia, 31 Aug. 1842., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:75)
    Re: MWTB's improvement in health; RWT's work load is great since RWT is the only one left in the Engineer Corps, the salary is greatly earned, have had no servant this year, have endured many hardships, RWT is resigning at the end of the year.
  - M[ary] W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Green Field, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 17 May 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:76)
    Re: events surrounding the death of Charles Braxton; MWB is concerned about MWTB's poor health; Mrs. Henry Webb had a bad fall; Lucy is in a family way again; Robert sent the accounts to Mr. Green; Aunt Short's death.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Green Field, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 25 Feb. 1844., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:77)
    Re: glad to know MWTB's baby is in good health; have had a great deal of company all winter; health news of family members.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpeper County, [Virginia]. 2 pp. ALS. 31 July 1844., pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:78)
    Re: MWTB's next visit to Falmouth and what to bring.
    Also includes a note by B[alsora] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpeper County, [Virginia]. Re: MWTB's next visit.
  - J[udy] H. [Tomlin] Coalter, Old Church, Hanover Co[unty], [Virginia], to Margaret [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, near Jeffersonton Post Office, Culpepper County, [Virginia], 1 Sept. 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:79)
    Re: have heard news of MWTB's new baby and MWTB's good health; health news of family.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper County, Virginia, 4 Sept. 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:80)
    Re: inquires about Papa's mouth and Walker's face; news of activities in Falmouth.
    Also includes a letter by L[ucy] M. [Barnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper County, Virginia Re: Baby Walker and winter vegetables.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Papa Mama" N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes and [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], Greenfield, Culpepper County, [Virginia], 15 Oct. 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:81)
    Re: Whig meetings with detailed commentary.
  - Olivia [?], Baltimore, [Maryland], to "Peggy" M[argaret] W. Barnes, Falmouth, Virginia, 28 Dec. 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:82)
    Re: news of the Christmas season.
    Also includes a letter by M[argaret] W. B[arnes], [?], to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Falmouth, Virginia Re: Christmas and family news.
  - M[argaret] [W.] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper County, Virginia, March 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:83)
    Re: obligations to study at school; health of friends and family; wishes that Bev and George could go to some good school.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 28 Feb. 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:84)
    Re: weather; health of family; activities of family.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Ditchley, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Jeffersonton, Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 8 Sept. 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:85)
    Re: health of family members and servants; weather; sewing projects; activities of family members.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper County, Virginia, 13 Oct. 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:86)
    Re: health of family members; general family news.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barne s, Greenfield, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 5 June 1847., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:87)
    Re: disagreement between William Braxton and Dr. Perkins and subsequent entanglements; news and health of family members; regrets MWTB's recent death of a child.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mother" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper County, Virginia, 6 Aug. 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:88)
    Re: news of activities since school broke.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Ditchley, [Virginia], to Margaret [W,] [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Jeffersonton P. O., Culpepper Co[unty], [Virginia], 11 Aug. 1847., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:89)
    Re: have had a "neurologic [?] affection of one side of my face and head" - has affected sight; health of family members; size of children in family; weather conditions.
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to George B. Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], 26 Apr. 1848., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:90)
    Also includes letters by M[argaret] W. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes] and "Papa" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia].
  - M[ary] W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Peggy" Margaret W. Barnes, Falmouth, Stafford Co[unty], [Virginia], 14 Nov. 1848., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:91)
    Re: trip to Richmond and shopping expedition; death of Mrs. Dick Smith; delight in visiting them all; brief family news.
  - Margaret W. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpepper County, Virginia, 12 Jan. 1849., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:92)
    Re: Aunt Lucy has gone to Chatham; Aunt Fanny and Bal had been sick; MWB has a dreadful cold; Cousin Nancy and Olivia are going to Chericoke; Bev and Walker send their love; how is George?; MWB supposes that Tomlin and Bev have to do their work.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], Presley, Virginia, to "Mama" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton P. 0., Culpepper County, Virginia, 26 Feb. 1849., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:93)
    Re: MWB is not at Chericoke but is staying with Aunt Judy here [Presley]; glad to know that George has entirely recovered; MWB likes staying here [Presley] inst ead of Chericoke because there isn't so much fuss and foolishness here [Presley] about dressing and having dinner parties - both of which MWB detests; having a quiet time with Uncle Robert and Aunt Judy; social occasions and visits by relatives; Aunt Judy is an "all powerful woman "; Tomlin's badness has not been mentioned to MWB; Uncle Robert and Harrison wish they could see you, but MWB does not believe a word of it.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Je[ffersonton], [Culpepper County], Virginia, 5 Mar. 1849., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:94)
    Re: wonders why BDB has not heard from MWTB or sister [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes] since BDB left; weather here is either snowy or rainy; general news of family and their health; death of Mr. Brook.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Presley, Virginia, to "Papa" N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes, Jeffersonton, Culpepper County, Virginia, 23 Mar. 1849., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:95)
    Re: traveling plans; death of Mr. Brooke; sunny weather; other family news.
  - Margaret W. Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Jeffersonton P. 0.], [Culpepper] [County], [Virginia], 20 Nov. 1849., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:96)
    Re: land purchase; family health news.
  Series 3: Correspondence, 1850-1869.
- Correspondence, 1850-1869., 49 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:97-145)
  - M[ary] W. B[raxton], Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 18 Jan. 1850., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:97)
    Re: the winter has been filled with much sickness and death; / affectionate comments on household slave, Louisa, catching on fire and dying 2 days later; Judy is making a trip to Gloucester; Walker's health has not been good this winter; Fanny looks remarkably well; heard there was a chance that MWTB might move near Falmouth - is it true?; who has written to whom; Dr. Braxton has had much to weigh him down - which has always affected his health; love to MWTB, Willy, and the boys.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Presley, [Virginia], to Tomlin [Barnes], n.p., 24 Feb. 1850., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:98)
    Re: glad TB's in school; behave and learn your lessons; the family misses you.
  - J[udy] H.. [Tomlin] Coulter, Presley, Virginia, to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Pinewood, Falmouth, Stafford County, [Virginia], 3 Jan. 1851., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:99)
    Re: apologetic towards JHTC and MWTB's lack of corresponding; rejoice in MWTB's being at Pinewood; JHTC's boys have left for the University; events of Christmas day; JHTC's given up all hopes of getting the place you heard of; love to Peggy, Willy, the boys, and the girls in Falmouth; St. sends his love to all.
  - Margaret [W.] Barnes, Chericoke, Virginia, to George B. Barnes, Falmouth, Virginia, 10 Feb. 1851., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:100)
    Re: scolds GBB for the lack of information in GBB's letter; Tomlin's starting school; messages to Mama and Papa; MWB sends love to the servants; requests George to get people to write to MWB.
  - 27 Feb. 1797. John W. Tomlin, William & Mary College, [Williamsburg], [Virginia], to "Father" [W.] [Tomlin], n.p. 4 pp. Cy. Copied at Clifton, [Virginia], Mar. 13, 1851., pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:101)
    Re: JWT fulfills a promise to send a composition or two - one about whether a republican government can exist and the other whether the circumstances of the Romans justified them in [?] their first dictator; JWT looks for money requested every day.
    Also includes a letter, n.d., by W. Tomlin, n.p., to John W. Tomlin, [William Mary College], [Williamsburg], [Virginia]. Re: received your composition which am well pleased with; irate discussion of JW's responsibility as a son to WT including JWT's extravagance with money, JWT 's education, etc. Cy.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 23 Sept. [l8]52., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:102)
    Re: glad to hear of George's improving [health]; "it seems to be rather hard for you all to understand me [BDB].. ." - BDB has received only kindness and affection from Uncle H[arrison?] -"as for the others with the exception of Armistead Braxton it has always been exactly the reverse.. ."; news of people staying at the Richmond House Mrs. Gordon talked of you and Papa incessantly; monetary value of Mrs. Gilsom's[?] farm compared to the value per acre of Pinewood.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, Virginia, to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Pinewood, Falmouth, Stafford Co[unty], [Virginia], 4 Apr. 1853., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:103)
    Re: MWB apologizes for long silence; Balsora is here [Chericoke] but is sick now; family news; MWB is behind in domestic chores; MWB's feelings toward children and anxiety caused by them; MWB's loneliness.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Lower Bremo, [Virginia], to Beverly Barnes, Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia, 22 Sept. 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:104)
    Re: MWB was annoyed by the short letter; describes a temperance spring and surrounding countryside; implies the family should visit Mama more.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], n.p., to Bal[sora] [Barnes], n.p., 1 Oct. 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:105)
    Re: arrangements to have MWB's shawl sent back to MWB.
  - Virginia B. Coalter, Richmond, [Virginia], to Beverley [Barnes], n.p., 8 Nov. 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:106)
    Re: thanks for BB's last letter; Mary's [?] wedding is next week - entertainment for the, wedding; the fair and all its animals; studying is important to VBC.
  - [Mary] [W.] [Braxton], Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 1 Feb. 1854., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:107)
    Re: beautiful spring-like weather; Mr. Webb has remarried and has brought home the new wife - events upon their arrival; general family information.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 12 May [l8]54., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:108)
    Re: BDB is disappointed that MWTB has only written BDB one letter; news items about sister [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes] and Walker and a recent attendance of a church service; love to all at home and in Falmouth - servants and all.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Papa" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], n.p., 13 July [18]54., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:109)
    Re: BDB is sending goods to NWBB via railroad; if George is better he should come down for he could get "an excellent situation"; the cholera is playing "mischief" here [Richmond].
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Papa" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], n.p., 2 Sept. [l8]54., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:110)
    Re: BDB hopes George will regain his health and strength; complains about BDB's tremendous appetite; sorry to hear of Walker's poor health; Mr. Braxton's barns with a whole crop of wheat burned and Braxton had no insurance; Betsy Braxton is being courted by Mr. Gatt[?] the Am. sculptor; BDB wants to see entire family and invites family down - assures family that the cholera is "nearly all gone".
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 9 Sept. [l8]54., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:111)
    Re: explanation for BDB's having not written sooner and why has the family not written to BDB?; after writing Uncle H[arrison?] please write and let BDB know what MWTB wrote for BDB doesn't want things to be kept a secret from him.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 8 Dec. [l8]54., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:112)
    Re: Armistead Braxton and Henrietta are to be married - details about marriage attendants and proposed activities; marriage of Powhatan Moncure and Dora Ashby - BDB wants news to be confirmed; the penitentiary burned down 7 Dec. 1854.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 13 Aug. [18]55., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:113)
    Re: BDB is sending goods to his MWTB via train; relates amusing incident pertaining to the song "Hug Eye"; reports yellow fever epidemic in Norfolk and Portsmouth.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], [Pinewood], [Virginia], 26 Jan. 1856., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:114)
    Re: long description of weather conditions in Chericoke and the resulting circumstances; MWB expresses feelings of unhappiness for those she loves who have suffered; limited work being done on plantation; sleighing activities; fire in Ingleside kitchen and servants lost nearly all their belongings, but it seems that all are well; family health and news items.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 3 May [l8]56., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:115)
    Re: BDB has sent items to MWTB that were requested in yesterday's letter via Stephen; BDB lists most items sent and requests acknowledgment of receipt from Aunt Fanny.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 1 July 1856., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:116)
    Re: departure of the girls from the house, their expected activities, and MWB's loneliness; proposed activities of MWB during the summer; reports illness of two people; requests news of MWTB's family.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 16 Mar. 1857., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:117)
    Re: Peggy's visit and her subsequent stranded situation on the other side of the river because of the ice; health news of several family members; the boat was destroyed and a new one was built; the progress of the garden; activities of family members.
  - B[everley] D. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 30 July [18]57., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:118)
    Re: BDB's severe illness and recovery; Walker's serious illness; Aunt Lucy's improving health; the birth of a daughter to Uncle Rob[er]t named Edenonia Fitzhugh [?] Tomlin; tell Sister [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes] that John Lawson is courting Bunny Braxton again.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], [Falmouth], [Virginia], 12 Oct. 1857., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:119)
    Re: birth of a daughter to Henrietta and circumstances thereafter; schedule of forth coming events including trips, Judy's birthday party, and winter projects; serious condition of Judy at Retreat, [Virginia] and of her expected death.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 25 Nov. 1857., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:120)
    Re: burdensome task of housekeeping and that work is done more out of duty than pleasure "as the members of the family drop off"; notes how changes have occurred over the last five years; trip to see Betty - reports on Betty's health, happiness, husband, and their fine living standards; message to Balsora via Margaret Barnes; invitation for MWTB and Peggy to spend the winter and see how Judy [H.] [Tomlin] Coulter's health has improved; events upon home coming.
  - A. G. Fricklen, n.p., to [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Pinewood, [Virginia], [c. 1858], 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:121)
    Re: feel most kindly for George in all his sufferings; will see MWTB tomorrow.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Chericoke, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 24 Feb. 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:122)
    Re: MWB understands that Peggy is to make a "profession of Religion" soon; hopes to spend several weeks with MWTB; mentions weather conditions; reports in length the illness of several family members; visits of friends and family; inquires about Fanny and Betty.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Balt[imore], [Maryland], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 28 Apr. 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:123)
    Re: expresses sorrow to "Margaret" [MWTB] and "Peggy" [MWB] in their loss of [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes]; MWB's forth-coming visit to see MWTB and "Peggy"[MWB]; sends love and prayers and sympathy.
    Also includes a letter by Aunt L[?], Balt[imore], [Maryland], to Bal[sora] [Barnes], n.p.
  - Mary W. Braxton, [Baltimore, Maryland?], to [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., [May 1858?]., 6 pages. ALS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 2:124)
    Re: William Braxton has given up the estate for MWB to manage; with no one to manage MWTB's place MWTB should rent out and hire out the servants; news of family and friends.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 27 July 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:125)
    Re: expresses sorrow to MWTB in the loss of a son, George, and glory in his heavenly home with the blessed savior; gives religious support in MWB's sympathy.
  - Mary W. Braxton, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Pine Wood, Falmouth, Stafford Co[unty], Virginia, 13 Aug. 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:126)
    Re: expresses sympathy in MWTB's loss of a son; Betty's confinement and the circumstances concerning the baby; understands from home that all are healthy but Virginia; Fanny Bland is to be married in the fall; activities in [Baltimore] - church too far away to attend; general family news.
    Also includes a letter written on the envelope by [?], to "Ma".
  - Nannie Oliver, White Sulphur Sp[rin]gs, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] Barnes, Pine Wood, near Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia, 10 Sept. 1858., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:127)
    Re: letter is written by Nannie for Harrison [Barnes], [MWTB's brother], because, HB has a lack of time to spare; HB knows of a position in Richmond that would be wonderful for Tomlin and encourages MWTB to use her influence to get Tomlin to apply: NO expresses her sympathy for MWTB's afflictions; [the Springs] have been deserted - only about 100 people on the grounds; thinks the position for Tomlin in Richmond is as an assistant with the Postmaster.
  - [Mary] [W.] [Braxton], Baltimore, [Maryland], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 16 Sept. 1858., 4 pages. LS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 2:128)
    Re: circumstances are such that MWB cannot visit MWTB at this time because Betty is not doing well, but the baby is fine - Betty needs help so as to not become ill; Fanny is to be married this fall and must have assistance in the preparations of the wedding.
  - [Mary] [W.] [Braxton], Baltimore, [Maryland], to Margaret [W] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 1 Oct. 1858., 4 pages. LS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 2:129)
    Re: Mr. Dallam is ill and has been in bed for more than 3 weeks; have no idea when leaving will be possible; health of Betty and baby and Mrs. Dallam; Fanny is to be married 11 Nov. and Fanny Coulter is to be married 10 Nov. [to a Mr. Brown].
  - F[rances] B[land] Coalter Brown, n.p. to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 9 March [18]59., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:130)
    Re: FBCB thinks of MWB often and would like to be of some service; MWB has seen so much trouble; religious information and instruction; FBCB has a good husband; Mama's, [Judy] [H.] [Tomlin] [Coalter], health is not good.